HEMENSE I. LAN

FULLSTACK ENGINEER

CONTACT

MOBILE: +234 701 105 6442

EMAIL: lihemen@gmail.com

WEBSITE: www.hemense.net

ADDRESS: Lokogoma, FCT, Nigeria

WORK EXPERIENCE

FRONTEND ENGINEER Sept 2022 - Present

AFEX Commodities Exchange Ltd.

- Sherlock Sherlock is a data visualization and natural language processor assistant. i developed the Self Service & Prompt Interfaces
- Workbench Workbench is an ERP Inventory management system. I built the CMS, Logistics management & Accounting modules
- ComX I worked on the Fixed Income submodule for Primary markets derivatives trading

WEB ENGINEER Oct 2021 - Sep 2022

Bluecaller Integrated Services Ltd.

- Bluecaller APi Worked on the recommendation engine for the choosing of services. I also worked on the Mapping Interface
- Zashaura Worked on building a Perfume Ecommerce application for an external client.

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING 2015-2021

Federal University of Technolog, Minna PMB 56, Minna, Niger State, Nigeria

CLOUD ENGINEERING 2022

Udacity

PROFILE

I am a highly skilled fullstack engineer with experience building for scale and distributed system. I excel at building business solutions and ensuring increased productivity and efficiency for organization. I have 3 years of experience developing websites, web apps, web servers and progressive web applications using HTML, Typescript, Node.js and React. I adopt a Functional Programming Paradigm with Test Driven Development and atomic design pattern to the development of applications.

ENGINEERING INTERN Jun 2020 - Aug 2020

Hotels.ng (HNG i7)

- Comments API i worked on a system-tosystem embedding comment microservice. I built part of the comment logging controllers
- Training I trained in the development and usage of backend architectures as well as unit and coverage tests.

SKILLS

- Typescript
- React, Next.js & tRPC
- HTML/CSS/SCSS
- MongoDB, PostgreSQL
- Unit & E2E Testing
- Javasript
- SEO
- DrizzleORM, Prisma ORM

COURSES & CERTIFICATION

- 1. Testing JavaScript by Kent C. Dodds
- 2. Javascript the Hard Parts by Frontend Mentors
- 3. Google Cloud Engineering by Google Africa Developer Scholarship
- 4. HackerRank Javascript (Intermediate)
 Certification

REFERENCE

GREEN ONYEJI

Head Design & Apps | AFEX gonyeji@africaexchange.com